Cincinnati, OH

jon.prell.dev@gmail.com

Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for JavaScript and four years of diverse professional experience in the field of Health and Safety as an EHS Professional. Looking to leverage my drive for continuous improvement into a new career as a Full-Stack Engineer.

#### Skills

- Programming, Database, and Markup Languages: Python, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS3
- Frameworks and Libraries: Flask, jQuery, Knockout.js, Bootstrap
- Additional Skills: Linux (Ubuntu distribution), AWS (Lightsail), Apache2 HTTP Server, Google APIs

# **Projects**

Portfolio Site

November 2017

- Professional portfolio site to provide prospective employers an opportunity to review my professional work.
- Deployed on a Python/Flask back-end and jQuery front-end.

### **Emergency Event Manager**

GitHub Link

GitHub Link

October 2017

- Real-time event mapping app to assist an Emergency Manager during a major disaster event.
- Built using Knockout's JavaScript library and MVVP framework, Google's JavaScript API, and FourSquare's API.

### **Safety Management System**

#### GitHub Link

August 2017

- Compliance system to help small businesses easily manage their recordkeeping within regulatory guidelines.
- Deployed using Python with PostgreSQL back-end architecture, 3<sup>rd</sup> party authentication, and Bootstrap front-end UI.

### **Work Experience**

Amazon.com

September 2015 – October 2017

**Safety Specialist** 

Hebron, KY

- Collaborated with operations team across 7 departments to reduce night shift injuries by 50% through training, concise reporting methodologies, and proactive engagement of the 1,500+ associates.
- Deployed StrongArm Tech's FUSE Platform to achieve a 33% reduction in injuries in the most high-risk departments and 0 muscle strain or ergonomic-related injuries for the associates participating in the program.
- Coordinated with Vaculux and Amazon Engineering to pilot a new material handling solution that generated a 10% increase in productivity with zero injuries on two test stations.

### **Marathon Petroleum Company**

#### -

August 2014 – August 2015

### Health, Environmental, Safety and Security Co-Op

Detroit, MI and Cincinnati, OH

- Authored site-specific emergency response procedures, facilitated emergency management training across 4 shifts, and coordinated with external emergency response agencies including the Cincinnati Fire and Police Departments.
- Collected noise dosimetry sampling data and produced a noise isopleth for the 250-acre MFD Refinery.

#### **Barnes Aerospace**

September 2013 – May 2014

## **Environmental Health and Safety Co-Op**

West Chester, OH

- Participated in 2 Kaizen events that reduced employee exposure to air contaminants by 66% while reducing waste.
- Inventoried 200+ individual machine items then rebuilt the work order system to reduce redundant work orders by 33% while improving regulatory compliance documentation processes.

#### **Kentucky Army National Guard**

February 2006 – February 2008

#### **Signals Intelligence Analyst**

## Louisville, KY

- Produced detailed analytical datasets from metadata intelligence for the 20<sup>th</sup> Special Forces Group (Airborne).
- Partnered with NCO Leadership in field support tasks during high-risk airborne operations with 0 injuries.

## **Education and Certification**

Udacity

www.udacity.com

Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree

November 2017

# **Eastern Kentucky University**

Richmond, KY

Master of Science in Safety, Security, Emergency Management

August 2015

Bachelor of Science in Homeland Security and Criminal Justice

May 2012